[Music]
what's up everybody this is Nick at
bobbin.com and we are talking about
getting huge getting swole getting
jacked on the best protein powders for
muscle gain but this is my actual voice
now protein is absolutely critical if
you're trying to gain muscle oh honestly
lose fat while retaining muscle as you
probably already know protein
unfortunately is the hottest
macronutrient to get the others are
carbs and fat it is not hard to get some
carbs and fat when you're stopping at
like a local gas station or just going
out on the road protein short of
carrying a little steamed chicken
breasts around in Ziploc bags it is
astonishingly hard to get in a
convenient way in an expensive way and
in a tasty way but fortunately that
problem has been recognized and these
companies here have all put out really
solid protein powders for muscle gain
and for muscle retention as well so
stick around we're gonna break down all
of the best protein powders for most
again including the best for the money
the best plant-based ones because yes
indeed they're a good solid plant-based
protein pads and also the best mirror
replacement if you really want to stack
on the extra carbs and fats along with
your protein so let's get started now
before I go any further I do need to
make it clear I'm not a medical
professional I'm a doctor and this is a
medical advice if you are making any
dramatic or minor changes to your
supplement regimen your workout regimen
your nutrition regimen make sure you
talk to your own doctor so that you know
that what you're doing isn't going to
conflict with your medical history your
medications or just your individual
nature so talk to your doctor before you
go ahead and buy any new supplements for
now let's talk about the best ones we've
tried
I know you clicking this video because
you want to find out what the best
protein powder for muscle gain is and
I'm just going to tell you because
that's why you're here and you seem like
a cool person right here Wolverine
fantastic name for the gentleman or
gentle lady looking to gain some muscle
Wolverine has a weight isolate here that
we really really like basically it's
nothing but protein powder right there's
some other stuff in here but what I mean
is the protein per calorie is very good
because it is way isolate so with 26
grams of protein you're just getting two
grams of carbs and half a gram of fat
and you've also got some digestive
enzymes in here to help the protein
break down more effectively and more
quickly more on that in a little bit but
I wanted to go into first the different
kinds of protein you're likely to find
in protein powders and the pros and cons
of each for status is way that's the
most popular one right now whey is a
byproduct of the cheese making process
so it used to be you separate the dairy
protein into the two types of protein in
milk which is case seen in a way use the
casein to make cheese you throw out the
way then we figured out the Whey is
actually a really bioavailable protein
it's actually the most easily absorbed
protein on Earth it's the most
bioavailable you can get and then we
figured out that we could dry it out and
turn to fun supplements like this where
you concentrate is the least processed
form of it it's the cheapest form as
well as a result although it also has
the most carbs and fat and lactose and
sugar it's not very high in them but it
still has more than the other options on
this list like whey isolate which is in
process in such a way is to strip out
much if not all of those carbs and fat
so if you want you can further process
where I slipped add some enzymes to it
and turn into way hydrolysis this is a
way that is so processed and broken down
that it is some people some people
consider it partially digested or
practically speaking they digests really
really quickly and there has been some
studies showing that like if you're an
elite athlete working out twice a day
way hydrolyzed it can make you regain
your power and regain your Effectiveness
more quickly than any level of way I do
want to make it clear that really just
applies to Elite athletes so the average
person when way isolate oh wait
concentrate is going to be fine plus
hydrolyzed way is super expensive and it
doesn't taste very good A lot of the
time because the amino acids have been
like uncoupled they're like free and
flying around anyway that's it for way
there's also casein as I mentioned
casein uh it is historically it's been
used in cheese making process right the
difference between casein and Whey
casein is much higher in calcium for one
but the main thing is that it digests
very slowly so when people want to have
a protein that is going to keep them
full for a long time they tend to take
casing because it breaks down slowly in
the stomach another interesting thing
about casing is that it forms a paste
very easily that's like another reason
why it digests slowly but it also means
if you add some water or even better
some whole milk into casein protein
powder you can make like some puddings
that are really quite tasting freeze
them turn them into ice cream that's
casein for you also we've got vegan
proteins as well with a couple of them
here there's a big sort of misconception
that there's no point taking vegan
protein powder because the amino acids
are not as complete as they are with
dairy now normally that's the case there
are some complete plant proteins out
there like a soy and amaranth and quinoa
but generally speaking animal proteins
have all essential amino acids in
roughly equal amounts which we call a
complete protein typically plant
proteins tend to be low in one or two
that said just about every plant-based
protein out there now plant-based
protein powder they combine a few
different proteins at once like rice and
pea to make a complete amino acid
profile and something that absorbs just
as well as a dairy protein so you do
have a lot of good options when it comes
to plant-based proteins as well so those
are the main categories of proteins that
we're going to go into and you're going
to see most of those on this list today
so let's get back into the top pick
[Music]
all right let's go into our list our
number one pick the best protein powder
for muscle gain is the very nice clean
formula from Wolverine as I mentioned
this is a whey isolate so it is very low
in carbohydrates and fetch the protein
per calorie is extremely high what
you've basically got here is a chicken
breast in a cup that actually tastes
delicious what's cool about Wolverine is
in addition to your chocolate milkshake
and your vanilla they've got some other
flavors the honey cinnamon peanut butter
one will change your life it's
absolutely fantastic but in addition to
that in addition to having the good
flavors and the good protein per calorie
the fact that's the way isolate which
means that again it's gonna be much much
lower in lactose and for some people it
may be more digestible this also has no
soy which bugs a lot of people who are
looking to gain muscle because there are
there are some folks who worry that any
amount of soy will potentially affect
your estrogen levels it won't I've done
a whole video on it but nonetheless if
you're convinced by the claims that
because you don't have to worry there's
no soy in this book no gluten either if
you're worried about that potentially
causing inflammation if you're someone
who's sensitive to it finally this has a
digestive enzyme blend of papine and
protease these are two enzymes that help
to break down protein and help you to
absorb it more effectively so those
reasons are why slaughtering you're
looking for a good solid protein powder
for muscle gain this gives you
everything you need and nothing you're
doing and it's also our favorite way I
slit as well uh we concentrate again
more lactose more sugar more fat
typically more flavor to be fatter
people who like whey concentrate I do
myself there are actually way Isis out
there with more carbs and more fat than
this in fact they managed to keep the
fat and the carbs so low while still
adding in extra flavorings and
sweeteners which tends to add a little
bit of carbohydrates that's a really
impressive feat so this is our favorite
whey protein isolate on the market and
also just generally a favorite protein
powder overall if your goal is muscle
gain
foreign
protein powder for muscle gain now look
we like Sovereign stuff a lot especially
at honey cinnamon peanut butter one but
the best most consistent offerings most
delicious flavors is huge supplements
check this out man this isn't just a
strawberry flavor it's strawberry
cheesecake flavor so you're getting the
strawberry and also a nice amount of
creaminess in there as well mix this up
with some milk especially whole milk but
even like lower fat non-fat milk maybe
even an almond milk this is just it's so
good and it just it adds more to the
strawberry flavor profile than we are
accustomed to getting on a big
strawberry guy myself and it's also not
just about the taste like this old has a
lot of protein per calorie as well it's
not quite as fantastic as Wolverine
right but nonetheless depending on the
flavor you get you're gonna get anywhere
from like I think it's like 23 to 26
grams of protein the shorty one is 23
and a half grams of protein I think six
grams of carbohydrates and three grams
of fat with that but truthfully
personally I'm usually pretty happy when
I see a good amount of carbs and fat in
a protein powder like that because let's
be honest practically speaking it's not
very much and usually it means the
flavor is going to be great as well so
you're getting extra flavor a tiny bit
of extra carbs and fat but practically
speaking when it fits into your overall
calories and macros it's not going to
make to the difference all besides
making a better tasting protein powder
before I go in I forgot to mention this
earlier if you would rather read a
version of this video right like if you
want to get this information but you
don't want to get it coming out of my
mouth or you want to have a look at some
of the studies and references we've been
talking about we have a written version
of this video if you want to check that
out and just go through that you can
just Google bub and best protein powders
for muscle gain it'll come right up so
you can check that out if you want to
digest this information that way but for
now let's talk about digesting some more
protein powders especially the best
price protein powder transparent Labs
has a really solid protein powder that
we think is one of the best best of us
again it's really good in value so we're
doing this is the best value protein
powder for muscle gain right what's cool
like transferring Labs there's a few
things the one is that they're very
transparent right if you go to the
website they'll always have like
citations full of studies that justify
why they include certain things in their
products right the protein powder it's a
bit more of a simple sort of endeavor
for them because the main ingredient is
just protein powder but it is grass-fed
whey isolate which is pretty cool so it
doesn't I slit so it's really low in
carbs and fat getting one gram of carbs
and zero grams of fat per scoop of 28
grams of protein so the protein per
calorie is just off the chain but
addition to that it's also grass-fed
which is pretty important for a lot of
folks so we think this is the best value
if you get a five pound tub it's going
to be just a dollar and 20 cents per
serving and remember that's 28 grams of
protein per serving which is more than
you're going to get in most protein
powders which typically hover between 20
and 25. so it really is phenomenal value
and on top of that we mean it's the best
natural protein powder because it's all
natural there's no artificial flavors or
sweeteners or colors or anything like
that plus there's no soy plus there are
no gums this is a really good
all-natural product because not only no
artificial flavors and sweeteners not
only are there no gums not only is it no
soy not only is it no gluten but also
the way it's grass-fed so if your
definition of all natural includes cows
that have like a more natural life that
depends when their lives cream into
feedlots or anything you can be pretty
confident with the selection of the whey
protein from transparent labs next up
we'll talk about the best vegan protein
powder for muscle game now
I like to say plant-based because vegan
has a lot of connotations a lot of
people just assume that something's
vegan it's not going to be any good
right now without having to emphasize
that you obviously eat you know spinach
and bananas and a whole bunch of vegan
stuff that you know is very good for you
uh Wolverine has a plant protein that is
really really uh really really effective
personally I'm not a vegan not on my
plant-based but I do like to have a
vegan protein powder in the mornings as
well and then I have a bunch of beef at
night it all kind of evens out why I
like this one from Wolverine the macros
are really impressive it is a lot harder
to build up a protein powder that is
plant-based it also is a lot of protein
per calorie because normally you're
getting these proteins from legumes
which are very much higher in
carbohydrates than protein or you're
getting from seeds which are much higher
in fat than protein so it can be very
hard to get a good macro balance that is
favorable to someone who's looking to
gain muscle but on this one they've
processed it in such a way they've
pulled off a protein powder that gives
you 22 grams of protein for just three
grams of carbohydrates and two and a
half grams of fat that is basically the
split you'll get from away concentrate
so that's really impressive you also
don't need to worry too much about the
amino acid profile because this is a
mixture of pea protein isolate and also
pumpkin protein so it helps to balance
it out and get a really nice sort of
amino isopropyl and especially you're
going to be getting plenty of leucine
which for most people is amino acid
they're most concerned with when it
comes to muscle gain so you've got a lot
of protein per calorie you've got a
really good spot amino acid it's all
natural as well so it's all natural
flavorings there's no soy in this
there's no gluten in it there's no GMOs
either and finally to test an
x-nutrition added into it so what's cool
if you happen to be a vegan this has 32
of your daily iron which can sometimes
be a little bit tricky to get not always
but sometimes it's a bit tricky to get
some get a lot of iron when you're in a
plant-based diet you've also got a good
amount of niacin phosphorus zinc
chromium chloride sodium and potassium
so that means that in addition to the
protein you're getting some electrolytes
help keep you hydrated too so whether or
not you are plant-based a product like
this can really go a long way now for
the moment you've all been waiting for
the best protein powder for Mass gaining
or the best mass gaining protein powder
I should say calories are of course the
number one component of gaining muscle
so while protein is great ideally you're
also getting clean of carbs and fat as
well but if you want any protein powder
that can double as a mirror placement
that has as many calories as your
standard meal you want to get a mass
gainer and this bad boy right here
transparent Labs Mass gaining supplement
is our absolute favorite for it check
this out in one serving of this which is
two gigantic Scoops that weigh about 200
grams you're gonna get 750 calories 14
grams of fat 110 grams of carbohydrates
and 53 grams of protein what that
bounces out to is a really nice one to
two ratio of protein to carbs which is
likely the minimum ratio of protein to
carbs you're going to be having in an
overall diet plan for gaining mass right
it's also pretty low in sugar I just
said it has 110 grams of carbs but it
has just 12 grams of sugar because a lot
of the carbohydrates come from tapioca
maltode question the way is grass fed
it's also got coconut milk powder in
here MCT oil there's some creatine in
here as well sweet potato powder for
some extra carbohydrates no artificial
flavors no artificial sweeteners is it a
little expensive yes it is it's about
five dollars per serving obviously
that's higher than the you know dollar
fifty to two dollars per serving and by
the way proteins but you have to
remember this has a good six times the
calories of these other protein powders
that we've been talking about so far so
the price is really just fine especially
when you remember again it's so low in
sugar and it's all natural which are
both close to the very unusual for Mass
gaining products make actually sad you
not go past transparent Labs Mass Gainer
and because it's so high in calories
it's very easy to make this taste
delicious which it does so next we've
got kind of a curious entry here because
the transparent Labs Mass Gainer has
about as many calories as a lot of
people would have in a scented meal but
this is not transparent Labs meal
replacement this one here is their mural
placement and so as a dedicated meal
replacement product we think this is
probably the best muscle gain as well
it's a lot more restrained in its
calorie count though right so if you are
really looking to gain serious masks get
as many calories as you can this is a
fantastic pick for that if you're
looking for a protein powder that just
has like some extra carbohydrates and a
fiber and fat to feel more full than an
average protein powder would we're a big
fan of this new replacement powder from
transparent Labs a couple cool things
about it uh so it's just 220 calories
for a scoop for a serving getting 24
grams of protein 19 grams of carbs 5
grams of fiber which is almost 20 of the
recommended intake and seven grams of
fat but also what you want to point out
here is that this is like pretty much
all transparent Labs as products if not
all of them it's all natural ingredients
so let's adjust mean there's no
artificial flavors or sweeteners it
means that the ingredients here come
from Whole Foods so the protein blend
isn't just wet you get whey isolate whey
concentrate grass-fed bone broth from
beef and also some egg white protein NP
Protein Isolate so if there's one thing
you know about gaining muscle is that
you want to get as many kind of protein
sources as you can get as many kinds of
foods that you can get as well so that
you're just getting as many a really
diverse array of nutrients and amino
acids this is a really good job of that
on top of that the rest of the
macronutrients are made up of products
like MCT oil there's cocoa powder flax
seed powder tapioca there's a pea starch
as well oat bran fiber Himalayan salt
and so on so it tastes pretty good
because it's not really really
restrained in calories but it's failure
spending calories for a meal replacement
and for a muscle gaining sort of product
so there's a lot of ways to fit into a
dedicated meal plan especially for those
who aren't really trying to pack on like
thousands of thousands and thousands of
calories in a day they just want
something that's going to get us some
protein and a little bit extra for them
to keep worrying about how many extra
bowls of rice you're gonna have to add
into their meal at dinner time big fan
of this one for the best mineral place
in for getting muscle next up we're
talking about the best digesting uh
protein powder for gaining muscle for
that we're going with caged whey protein
isolate big fan of this one so this has
120 calories in 20 25 grams of protein 3
grams of carbs with one gram of fiber
half a gram of fat the reason we put
this as the best digesting is because it
has the interesting blend of amino acids
from a company called prohydrolase and
what's cool about getting digestive
enzymes from a Big Brand like that as
opposed to just adding individual
enzymes like say so Wolverine does like
they put in paparian and protease that's
great and there's definitely interesting
evidence supporting that prohydrases
though it's a proprietary blend created
by this company which means they've been
able to carry out published studies to
measure its Effectiveness so with a
company like prohydrase we have more
concrete evidence it's like more
concrete numbers as to like how well it
improves digestion and absorption so
they've done like two double-blind
placebo-controlled human studies and
some in vitro stuff as well that I found
like up to 20 more branched chain amino
acids in the blood when you're putting
these suggested enzymes in with some
protein powder so that's like that's a
very interesting area of research and
also they've found that it can help to
reduce discomfort from people with
sensitive stomachs and that sort of
thing now obviously that is something to
talk about with your doctor nonetheless
I would encourage you to check out the
website to see the sorts of conditions
that it's been able to help with because
a lot of the time if you have a sense of
stomach adding an enzymes can help again
this is getting a little bit too
medically here so I do really to
emphasize to talk to your doctor about
this and the last there's a good chance
you're going to hear that our enzymes
can sometimes be a potential cure for
these sorts of subjects talk to your
doctor but still in of all the
approaching Powers I've got here from
muscles again we definitely find that
cage is the best for digestion the last
entry on our list is the best hydrolyzed
protein powder for muscle gain if you
remember way back several years ago when
I began this video I talked about the
differences between whey concentrate
isolate and hydrolicit hydrolyzed away
generally doesn't taste as great and
generally is much more expensive but
Dymatize has put together one that is
actually pretty great tasting and pretty
inexpensive the reason for that is this
isn't a hydrolyzed whey protein powder
as much as it is a hydrolyzed whey
protein powder product by that I mean
the protein in this is a mixture of
hydrolyzed whey anime eye slit which
helps to save a bit of money and improve
the taste however the first ingredient
on the ingredients list is hydrolyzed
away so they haven't just like put in a
couple of grains of hydrolyzed away and
said this counts as a hydrolyzed product
you know what I mean it is majority
hydrolyzed way and again if you recall
the reset the hydrolyzed way suggests
that it is so broken down and so
processed that it borders on
pre-digested so it absorbs like very
very quickly which can be helpful if you
are really hungry or if you have like
really worked out and your stomach's
really empty or if you are training
multiple times a day and you need to
recover faster than you would otherwise
again this has a mixture with whey
isolate but still this is definitely the
best bet if you are curious about the
potential benefits of hydrolyzed whey
and also if you just want a really
really lean crochet powder because it
says 25 grams of protein one gram of
carbs and zero grams of fat so whether
you care about hydralized weight or not
this is a pretty good pick and also
finally this is tested by informed
Choice which is a third-party tester
that makes sure there are no Bend
substances in this so given as athletes
who are usually instant hydrolyzed away
you probably if you're an athlete and
you want to try out this product you'll
be glad to know this is also a
third-part tested for advanced
substances so you are in the clear bonus
the cinnamon flavor tastes really really
good so that does it for our list of the
best protein powders for muscle gain
um before I leave you I do just want to
note like things to keep in mind when
you are trying to gain muscle right
because a lot of folks they'll like be
Googling like best protein powders or
gaining muscle and they'll think okay
I'll add a scoop of this and then I'll
be done the actual way that the people
who have these astonishing buddies and
big hulking figures the way that they
gain muscle is not by just paying
attention to supplements is that paying
attention to the overall calories the
protein the carbohydrates the fat their
sleep and their workouts this is also if
you want to get dialed in so that you
don't risk disappointment because you
just spent 30 bucks in a protein powder
tub you figured to take a scoop a day
and it's suddenly you're going to get
jacked what I really what's really
important here is to make sure that you
know how many calories you're burning in
a day and also making sure that you are
in slight excess of that while combined
with a good resistance training regimen
to get you there we have a calculator on
bar Ben to help you to calculate you the
amount of calories and certain
macronutrients that you need to consume
if that is your goal I encourage you to
give that a Google just like bar Ben
macro calculator and that'll be a really
good way to get you started so as much
as there are a lot of high and mighty
people in the nutrition world who like
to say like supplements mean nothing
supplements are really useful and
convenient and inexpensive one like a
per gram of protein basis they
definitely have a place and like through
sheer convenience of a protein powder
it's definitely good to get some protein
powder if muscle gain is your goal you
just need to remember all the rest of
the piece of the puzzle as well that
said I am a sport supporter interview
athletes for a living I don't know any
of them that don't take protein powder
on the reg and if you have watched this
video up until now I am positive that
you have found a approach about the
muscle again that's going to work for
you
that's our video man make sure you
Google the full article if you want to
read this all out that's just like
bobbin plus best approach powder for
muscle gain otherwise I'll catch you
next video
[Music]
laughs